Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
♪Passing by where leaves fall and flowers fade♪
♪المرور حيث تتساقط الأوراق وتذبل الزهور♪
♪Chancing upon shooting stars and northern lights♪
♪الصدفة على النجوم المتساقطة والأضواء الشمالية♪
♪At this moment, I borrow the wind♪
♪في هذه اللحظة، أستعير الريح♪
♪To set sail for distant seas♪
♪للإبحار إلى البحار البعيدة♪
♪Rumors swirl close to my ears♪
♪تدور الشائعات بالقرب من أذني♪
♪Some laugh and say my dreams are wild♪
♪يضحك البعض ويقولون أن أحلامي جامحة♪
♪Yet I will not change my original aspiration♪
♪ولكنني لن أغير طموحاتي الأصلية♪
♪Even if it means running into a wall♪
♪حتى لو كان ذلك يعني الاصطدام بالحائط♪
♪I know the road to growing up brings pain♪
♪أعلم أن الطريق إلى النمو يجلب الألم♪
♪Still, I hold fast to the dream I cherish♪
♪ما زلت متمسكًا بالحلم الذي أعتز به♪
♪Never have I thought to yield♪
♪لم أفكر أبدًا في الاستسلام♪
♪Youth is meant to stand against the world♪
♪الشباب هو من المفترض أن يقف في وجه العالم♪
♪I've always longed♪
♪لقد تمنيتها دائما♪
♪To stand upon the highest peak♪
♪الوقوف على أعلى قمة♪
♪I've always wished♪
♪لقد تمنيت دائما♪
♪To cross a river wide and deep♪
♪لأعبر نهرًا واسعًا وعميقًا♪
♪In darkness, look up to see the sky turn clear♪
♪في الظلام، انظر إلى الأعلى لترى السماء تصبح صافية♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪The butterfly reborn from its cocoon must fly♪
♪الفراشة المولودة من شرنقتها يجب أن تطير♪
♪Like bamboo breaking forth, I chase dreams through hardship♪
♪مثل الخيزران الذي ينبت، أطارد الأحلام من خلال المشقة♪
♪Return to me, my dream♪
♪ارجع إليّ يا حلمي♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪My pure heart stays the same♪
♪قلبي النقي يبقى كما هو♪
♪You must face the wind♪
♪يجب عليك مواجهة الريح♪
♪And go where your heart leads♪
♪واذهب إلى حيث يقودك قلبك♪
♪Embrace the moonlight that belongs to you♪
♪احتضن ضوء القمر الذي ينتمي إليك♪
♪In the dark♪
♪في الظلام♪
=Voyage to Haihun, Season 2=
=رحلة إلى هايهون، الموسم الثاني=
=Episode 1=
=الحلقة 1=
(Where am I?)
(أين أنا؟)
(Looks like I messed up this round.)
(يبدو أنني أفسدت هذه الجولة.)
(Let me restart then.)
(دعني أبدأ من جديد إذن.)
How long has it been?
كم من الوقت مضى؟
Two days.
يومان.
Our men from Changyi will still die.
رجالنا من تشانغي سوف يموتون أيضًا.
And so will you.
وأنت أيضًا ستفعل ذلك.
So, why not risk it all?
إذن، لماذا لا نجازف بكل شيء؟
Heng.
هنغ.
What on earth happened?
ماذا حدث على الأرض؟
- Wait for me to wake up. - Wang Heng.
- انتظرني حتى أستيقظ. - وانغ هينج.
Heng.
هنغ.
Don't forget.
لا تنسى.
You're the uncertain fate I've been waiting for.
أنت المصير المجهول الذي كنت أنتظره.
(Right, Liu He is still waiting for me to save him.)
(حسنًا، ليو هي لا يزال ينتظرني لإنقاذه.)
(I can't die.)
(لا أستطيع أن أموت.)
Heng.
هنغ.
Help me.
ساعدني.
De Jiu.
دي جيو.
Heng, you're awake.
هينج، أنت مستيقظ.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Lady De Jiu isn't in danger for now.
السيدة دي جيو ليست في خطر في الوقت الراهن.
Heng.
هنغ.
Why is it you two?
لماذا أنتما الاثنان؟
What happened in Wucheng Village?
ماذا حدث في قرية ووتشنغ؟
A troop from the Western Regions suddenly arrived.
فجأة وصلت قوات من المناطق الغربية .
I didn't get a clear look at them,
لم أحصل على نظرة واضحة لهم،
and you and De Jiu
وأنت ودي جيو
were trapped in deadly peril.
كانوا محاصرين في خطر مميت.
I could only take you through the secret tunnel.
لا أستطيع أن آخذك إلا عبر النفق السري.
What about our men from Changyi?
ماذا عن رجالنا من تشانغيي؟
What about them?
ماذا عنهم؟
As for what happened later,
وأما ما حدث بعد ذلك،
I have no idea.
ليس لدي أي فكرة.
What time is it now?
ما هو الوقت الآن؟
What time is it?
أي ساعة؟
Heng.
هنغ.
You're gravely wounded.
لقد أصبت بجروح خطيرة.
Going now will do no good.
الذهاب الآن لن يجدي نفعا.
Besides, Liu He...
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، ليو هي...
Liu He has been deposed.
لقد تم عزل ليو هي.
Heng.
هنغ.
All those careful plans...
كل تلك الخطط المدروسة...
Still, man's plans can't match Heaven's.
ومع ذلك، فإن خطط الإنسان لا يمكن أن تتطابق مع خطط السماء.
Kang, I'll repay this life-saving grace someday.
كانج، سأرد لك هذه النعمة التي أنقذت حياتي يومًا ما.
My bond with Liu He remains.
لا تزال علاقتي مع ليو هي قائمة.
I must see him.
يجب أن أراه.
Lady Xu.
السيدة شو.
Look after De Jiu for me.
اعتني بـ دي جيو من أجلي.
Heng.
هنغ.
Hyah!
هيا!
Indecision
التردد
leads to chaos.
يؤدي إلى الفوضى.
Indecision...
التردد...
Hyah!
هيا!
(Duke of Changyi's Mansion)
(قصر دوق تشانغي)
Whoa.
واو.
Lord Wang.
اللورد وانغ.
Is the Duke of Changyi still here?
هل دوق تشانغي لا يزال هنا؟
He went to Wucheng Village to find you.
لقد ذهب إلى قرية ووتشنغ للبحث عنك.
Hyah!
هيا!
Quick, run!
سريعا، أركض!
Run!
يجري!
Hyah!
هيا!
He deposed me just to make it easier to kill me, right?
لقد عزلني فقط لتسهيل قتلي، أليس كذلك؟
Come on!
تعال!
I have never known fear.
لم أعرف الخوف أبدًا.
Hyah!
هيا!
(Still, I'm too late.)
(لا أزال متأخرًا جدًا.)
Liu He,
ليو هي،
I'll save you
سأنقذك
once more.
مرة أخرى.
(14th day of the 8th month, 74 BC)
(اليوم الرابع عشر من الشهر الثامن سنة 74 ق.م)
Heng, you're awake!
هينج، أنت مستيقظ!
Heng!
هنغ!
Lady Xu.
السيدة شو.
Please take care of De Jiu.
من فضلك اعتني بـ دي جيو.
Kang, find Lord Xu for me.
كانغ، ابحث عن اللورد شو بالنسبة لي.
Have him bring men to rescue Wucheng Village.
اطلب منه أن يحضر رجالاً لإنقاذ قرية ووتشينج.
Heng!
هنغ!
(I must make it in time.)
(يجب أن أتمكن من ذلك في الوقت المناسب.)
(This time, I must make it in time.)
(هذه المرة، يجب أن أصل في الوقت المحدد.)
(Liu He.)
(ليو هي.)
(Hold on.)
(يتمسك.)
Over there.
هناك.
Heng.
هنغ.
Hurry, save him.
اسرعوا انقذوه
- Quick. - Heng.
- سريعًا. - هنغ.
You're finally awake.
لقد استيقظت أخيرا.
Here.
هنا.
Let me help you up.
دعني أساعدك.
Qingge.
كينغج.
Where are we heading?
إلى أين نحن متجهون؟
We're on the road back to Changyi.
نحن في الطريق للعودة إلى تشانغي.
Changyi?
تشانغي؟
Yeah.
نعم.
But I went to Wucheng Village.
ولكن ذهبت إلى قرية ووتشنغ.
When I reached Wucheng Village,
عندما وصلت إلى قرية ووتشنغ،
Lord Xu had saved you.
لقد أنقذك اللورد شو.
Lord Xu...
اللورد شو...
You must be looking for this.
لا بد أنك تبحث عن هذا.
When you were unconscious, you held it tight in your hand.
عندما كنت فاقدًا للوعي، كنت تمسكه بقوة في يدك.
What about them?
ماذا عنهم؟
Are they with us?
هل هم معنا؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Where are they now?
أين هم الآن؟
Where are they?
أين هم؟
It's all my fault.
إنه خطئي كله.
If I had sent a warning sooner,
لو أرسلت تحذيرًا في وقت سابق،
this tragedy wouldn't have happened.
هذه المأساة لم تكن لتحدث.
It's all on me.
كل هذا عليّ.
They're all gone?
لقد رحلوا جميعا؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
All of them are gone?
هل رحلوا جميعا؟
How could that be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
How could they all be gone?
كيف يمكن أن يرحلوا جميعا؟
It's my fault.
إنه خطئي.
I was the one who sent them to ruin.
أنا من أرسلهم إلى الهلاك.
I will join them.
سوف انضم اليهم
Liu He, Liu He...
ليو هي، ليو هي...
They're already gone.
لقد رحلوا بالفعل.
What's the point in doing this now?
ما الهدف من القيام بهذا الآن؟
It's alright. I'm still here.
لا بأس، أنا مازلت هنا.
I'll stay by your side.
سأبقى بجانبك.
I'll be here with you.
سأكون هنا معك.
But they're all gone.
ولكنهم جميعا رحلوا.
They're all gone.
لقد رحلوا جميعا.
It's all because of me.
كل هذا بفضلي.
Ah!
اه!
(Changyi)
(تشانغيي)
You can't even ride.
لا يمكنك حتى الركوب.
How are you different from the useless?
كيف تختلف عن عديم الفائدة؟
You fool.
يا أحمق.
Who says one must ride to manage horses?
من قال أنه يجب على الإنسان أن يركب الخيل لإدارة الخيول؟
Don't you want to see the Duke?
ألا تريد رؤية الدوق؟
The first "Changyi Riders"
أول "فرسان تشانغي"
"Racing with the Wind".
"السباق مع الريح"
The finals begin now!
تبدأ النهائيات الآن!
Go for it!
أذهب خلفها !
Ride faster later.
ركوب أسرع في وقت لاحق.
(Changyi)
(تشانغيي)
Wang Heng.
وانغ هنغ.
You're the last one.
أنت الأخير.
My apologies.
اعتذاري.
I drank too much alone last night.
لقد شربت كثيرًا بمفردي الليلة الماضية.
It cost me some time.
لقد كلفني بعض الوقت.
Liu He.
ليو هي.
Yes?
نعم؟
(Qingge Tavern)
(حانة كينغج)
This is the ad space I've prepared
هذه هي مساحة الإعلان التي قمت بإعدادها
for our esteemed patrons.
لعملائنا الكرام.
All prime spots for display.
جميع المواقع الرئيسية للعرض.
Take a look here.
إلق نظرة هنا.
The horse's neck, the horse's belly,
رقبة الحصان، بطن الحصان،
and the most expensive spot here,
والمكان الأغلى هنا،
which is called the Flattery Seat.
وهو ما يسمى بمقعد التملق.
What brings you all here?
ما الذي أتى بكم جميعا هنا؟
Heng.
هنغ.
Bushi.
شجيرة.
- Li Qi. - Duke.
- لى تشى. - دوق.
Liu He.
ليو هي.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
(Duke of Guangling's Mansion)
(قصر دوق قوانغلينغ)
Du.
ل.
Du, what's wrong?
دو، ما الخطب؟
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Since Liu He has been dethroned,
منذ خلع ليو هي من العرش،
leaving him to linger on
تركه ليبقى
matters little.
لا يهم كثيرا.
I am now the sole heir to the throne.
أنا الآن الوريث الوحيد للعرش.
This is Heaven's will.
هذه هي إرادة السماء.
Since the remnants of Changyi
منذ بقايا تشانغيي
no longer serve any use,
لم تعد ذات فائدة
why not wipe them all out
لماذا لا نقضي عليهم جميعا
to prevent future troubles?
لمنع المشاكل المستقبلية؟
We'll do as you say.
سوف نفعل كما تقول.
Bring them in.
أدخلهم.
Du.
ل.
He's going to kill us.
إنه سيقتلنا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Out. Move.
اخرج. تحرك.
- Move. - Where are you taking me?
- تحرك. - إلى أين تأخذني؟
Take them away.
خذهم بعيدا.
Move.
يتحرك.
On your knees.
على ركبتيك.
Your Highness, they're here.
سموكم، إنهم هنا.
Kill them.
اقتلوهم
Spare me! I have things to report.
انقذوني! لدي أشياء أريد أن أخبركم بها.
I can ensure that you live a long life.
أستطيع أن أضمن لك أن تعيش حياة طويلة.
Well.
حسنًا.
You lowly commoner.
أيها المواطن البسيط.
How could you manage that?
كيف تمكنت من ذلك؟
Duke.
دوق.
I know Liu He has a sacred item.
أعرف أن ليو هي لديه شيء مقدس.
It's the Qilin.
إنه تشيلين.
It can grant you a long life.
يمكن أن يمنحك حياة طويلة.
A long and healthy life.
حياة طويلة وصحية.
Oh?
أوه؟
Explain in detail.
اشرح بالتفصيل.
Just say the spell,
فقط قل التعويذة
and the Qilin will glow from head to toe.
وسوف يتوهج تشيلين من الرأس إلى أخمص القدمين.
Any wish can then come true.
ومن ثم يمكن لأي أمنية أن تتحقق.
Does such a thing really exist?
هل يوجد مثل هذا الشيء فعلا؟
I saw it with my own eyes.
لقد رأيته بأم عيني.
Where is the Qilin now?
أين هو تشيلين الآن؟
Before reaching Chang'an,
قبل الوصول إلى تشانغآن،
it was seized by Huo Guang.
تم الاستيلاء عليها من قبل هوو قوانغ.
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
Is what you said
هل هذا ما قلته
all true?
هل كل هذا صحيح؟
Every word is true.
كل كلمة صحيحة.
Only Liu He knows the spell.
فقط ليو هي يعرف التعويذة.
I am his confidant.
أنا صديقه المقرب.
I can help you get the spell.
يمكنني مساعدتك في الحصول على التعويذة.
Li Nvxu.
هذا كل شيء.
Yes.
نعم.
Set out for Chang'an at once.
انطلق إلى تشانغآن على الفور.
I will soon ascend the throne.
سأعتلي العرش قريبا.
Make the necessary arrangements
اتخاذ الترتيبات اللازمة
and lobby when needed in Chang'an.
والضغط عندما تكون هناك حاجة لذلك في تشانغآن.
While you're at it,
بينما أنت في ذلك،
see if the Qilin is with Huo Guang.
انظر إذا كان Qilin مع Huo Guang.
Yes.
نعم.
(Three years later, in 71 BC,)
(بعد ثلاث سنوات، في عام 71 قبل الميلاد)
(Xu became)
(أصبح شو)
(the Empress.)
(الامبراطورة)
(Huo Xian)
(هو شيان)
(killed Xu,)
(قتل شو)
(and Huo Chengjun)
(وهو تشنغ جون)
(entered)
(دخل)
(the Palace,)
(القصر)
(leading to the downfall.)
(مما يؤدي إلى السقوط.)
Liu He.
ليو هي.
That makes it the 351st time.
وهذا يجعلها المرة 351.
San.
سان.
Do I look like her?
هل أشبهها؟
I'm talking to you.
انا اتحدث معك.
(It's been three years.)
(لقد مرت ثلاث سنوات.)
(Every remedy has been tried, yet he's still in a coma.)
(تم تجربة كل العلاجات، لكنه لا يزال في غيبوبة.)
Are you the one closest to him?
هل أنت الأقرب إليه؟
Are you?
أنت؟
I suppose so.
أعتقد ذلك.
Good.
جيد.
The gloom has long settled in his heart.
لقد استقر الكآبة في قلبه منذ فترة طويلة.
Only if one dear to him offers love and care
فقط إذا قدم له شخص عزيز عليه الحب والرعاية
can the illness be cured.
هل يمكن علاج المرض؟
Breath meeting breath
لقاء التنفس مع التنفس
is a fine remedy to awaken the spirit.
يعتبر علاجًا جيدًا لإيقاظ الروح.
With a gentle touch of your lips,
مع لمسة لطيفة من شفتيك،
warmth will pour into the deepest valley,
سوف يتدفق الدفء إلى أعمق الوادي،
reaching the hidden chambers of the soul,
الوصول إلى الغرف الخفية للروح،
clearing the mind's haze,
إزالة ضباب العقل،
and stirring tender yearning within.
وتحريك الشوق الرقيق في الداخل.
Utter nonsense.
هذا هراء تماما.
Nonsense.
هراء.
♪Words drift and waver in the wind♪
♪الكلمات تتجول وتتمايل في الريح♪
♪Leaving feelings stuck at the throat♪
♪ترك المشاعر عالقة في الحلق♪
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
I'll give it a try anyway.
سأحاول ذلك على أية حال.
♪My gaze met the dark waves♪
♪نظرتي التقت بالأمواج المظلمة♪
♪I raised a cup to hide my restless heart♪
♪رفعت كأسًا لأخفي قلبي المضطرب♪
♪My little courage turned into falling snow♪
♪شجاعتي الصغيرة تحولت إلى تساقط الثلوج♪
♪A thousand words stuck at the edge♪
♪ألف كلمة عالقة على الحافة♪
♪Between my fingers♪
♪بين أصابعي♪
♪Spilling shards of starlight♪
♪تناثر شظايا من ضوء النجوم♪
♪The fire in my chest♪
♪النار في صدري♪
♪Ignited the burning night♪
♪أشعلت الليل المحترق♪
♪Watch the storm; hear the night rain fall♪
♪شاهد العاصفة؛ استمع إلى صوت هطول المطر في الليل♪
♪Till the light of dawn♪
♪حتى ضوء الفجر♪
♪A truth that cannot be spoken♪
♪حقيقة لا يمكن التحدث بها♪
♪Right and wrong matter♪
♪الصواب والخطأ مهمان♪
♪Yet I can't make the right choice♪
♪ولكن لا أستطيع اتخاذ الاختيار الصحيح♪
♪The lost player in the game♪
♪اللاعب الخاسر في اللعبة♪
♪Made a move by a twist of fate♪
♪لقد اتخذت خطوة بسبب تقلب القدر♪
♪The way back is lost, leaving nowhere to return♪
♪لقد ضاع طريق العودة، ولم يبق مكان للعودة♪
♪Borrow the endless cycles♪
♪استعارة الدورات التي لا نهاية لها♪
♪To fight for the most perfect outcome♪
♪القتال من أجل الحصول على النتيجة الأكثر مثالية♪
♪How to trace the threads and follow cause and effect♪
♪كيفية تتبع الخيوط واتباع السبب والنتيجة♪
♪Seeking a strategy without flaw♪
♪البحث عن استراتيجية خالية من العيوب♪
♪How to break free from this fated yet unforeseen lock♪
♪كيفية التحرر من هذا القفل المقدر وغير المتوقع♪
♪To live so as to shake the world♪
♪العيش من أجل هز العالم♪
♪With this journey, I gain a fiercer edge♪
♪مع هذه الرحلة، اكتسبت حافة أكثر شراسة♪
♪I've planned before I act countless times♪
♪لقد خططت قبل أن أتصرف مرات لا تحصى♪
♪Fatal danger turned into a jest♪
♪خطر قاتل تحول إلى مزحة♪
♪Through this road, I watch the endless rise and fall♪
♪من خلال هذا الطريق، أشاهد الصعود والهبوط الذي لا نهاية له♪
♪In the chapters lie ages of decay and bloom♪
♪في الفصول تكمن عصور من الاضمحلال والازدهار♪
♪Let us meet again♪
♪دعونا نلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪One hurried path, and one at ease♪
♪مسار واحد سريع، ومسار آخر مريح♪